- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
*
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[cheerful ukulele music]
【欢快的尤克里里音乐】
*
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
[foghorn blares]
[雾号声]
[mumbles indistinctly]
[含糊不清地咕哝]
[crash]
[碰撞]
- Meow, meow, meow, meow.
- 喵，喵，喵，喵。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Yeah, I am ripped.
- 是的，我被撕裂了。
- [grumbling meows]
- [抱怨的喵声]
- [mumbles]
- [咕哝]
- Meow!
- 喵！
Meow.
喵。
[snoring]
[打鼾]
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
Whoa!
哇！
[thud]
[砰]
[eyes pop]
[groans]
[眼睛突出]
[呻吟]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[steam hisses]
[蒸汽嘶嘶声]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[clunk]
[groans]
[沉闷]
[呻吟]
- Hey there, have you recently
been involved in an accident?
- 嘿，你最近有吗
遭遇过事故吗？
Well, have you?
- Well, yes. Yes, I have.
嗯，你有吗？
- 嗯，是的。是的，我有。
- Well, then you need
life insurance.
- 那么你需要
人寿保险。
- Life insurance?
- 人寿保险？
- What?
Is there an echo in here?
- 什么？
这里有回声吗？
Do yourself a favor, kiddo.
帮自己一个忙，孩子。
Sign here,
and you'll be protected.
在这里签名，
你会受到保护。
- I--hmm? No.
Um...no.
- 我--嗯？不。
嗯...不。
[rubber duck squeaks]
Wait--no.
[橡皮鸭吱吱声]
等等——不。
Wait--
- Here!
等等——
- 在这里！
- Ah!
Okay, thanks.
- 啊！
好的，谢谢。
[pen squeaking]
[钢笔吱吱作响]
- And while you're at it,
clumsy, why not buy two?
- 当你这样做的时候，
笨拙，为什么不买两个呢？
- Okay.
[pen squeaking]
- 好的。
[钢笔吱吱作响]
- [laughs gleefully]
- [高兴地笑]
[knock at door]
- Ooh!
[敲门]
- 哦！
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
- Hey, SpongeBob!
You're in your underwear.
- 嘿，海绵宝宝！
你穿着内衣。
That's cool.
这很酷。
I got your mail.
我收到你的邮件了。
What is it?
它是什么？
[elastic stretches and pops]
[弹性拉伸和弹出]
- It's my life insurance.
I got one for you too.
- 这是我的人寿保险。
我也给你准备了一份。
- Oh, boy! Life insurance!
- 哦，孩子！人寿保险！
[boinging]
Life insurance!
[轰鸣声]
人寿保险！
Life insurance!
[crash]
人寿保险！
[碰撞]
Life insurance!
人寿保险！
What's life insurance?
什么是人寿保险？
- I'm not sure,
but I think it means
- 我不确定，
但我认为这意味着
that for the rest of our lives,
we are protected.
在我们的余生中，
我们受到保护。
We can't get hurt.
我们不能受伤。
- Mm...
- 毫米...
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
[spits]
The contract tastes legitimate,
[吐口水]
合同味道合法，
but I don't believe it.
但我不相信。
- Well, let's try to get hurt,
and we'll see.
- 好吧，让我们试着受伤吧，
我们拭目以待。
- Ha! Well, finally,
something I'm good at.
- 哈！好吧，最后，
我擅长的事情。
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
[grunts]
- Remarkable.
[咕哝]
- 了不起。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- You can hit me all you want...
- [grunts]
- 你想打我就打吧...
- [咕哝]
- Yet I can't be damaged.
- 但我不能被伤害。
This life insurance
is really working.
这份人寿保险
确实有效。
- [grunts]
I've become unbreakable!
- [咕哝]
我已经变得坚不可摧了！
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
[relaxing music]
[轻松的音乐]
- Why, yes, I do race
sea horses.
- 为什么，是的，我参加比赛
海马。
[squishy smash]
[laughter and grunting]
[软软的粉碎]
[笑声和咕哝声]
Oh, I don't know
if I'd call myself
哦，我不知道
如果我打电话给自己
an international playboy.
国际花花公子
[laughter and grunting]
[growls]
[笑声和咕哝声]
[咆哮]
[both laughing]
- [grunts]
[两人都笑了]
- [咕哝]
- [laughs]
[bonk]
- [笑]
[棒棒哒]
- Just what are you two
ignorami doing out here?
-你们两个到底是什么人
无知的人在这里做什么？
- We're trying to hurt
each other.
- 我们试图伤害
彼此。
- Oh!
- Don't--hey--what the--
- 哦！
- 别--嘿--那是什么--
- You got a sea spider
on your head.
- 你有一只海蜘蛛
在你的头上。
- It's not a sea spider,
you dope.
- 这不是海蜘蛛
你这个笨蛋。
It's my hair.
这是我的头发。
both: Mm...
两人：嗯……
[bonking and laughter]
[碰撞和笑声]
- Wait a second.
Hurt each other?
- 等一下。
互相伤害？
Oh, I'm gonna enjoy
seeing this.
哦，我会享受的
看到这个。
- [laughs]
[clunk]
- [笑]
[沉闷]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Whoa!
[boing]
哇！
[嗡嗡声]
[both laugh]
[两人都笑了]
- Stop! Stop! Stop!
- 停止！停止！停止！
I thought you said you were
trying to hurt each other.
我以为你说你是
试图伤害对方。
- Uh-huh, we're trying.
- 嗯嗯，我们正在努力。
- Well, you're not
gonna do any damage
- 好吧，你不是
会造成任何伤害
with soft pillows.
和柔软的枕头。
Here, try this.
来，试试这个。
- Okay.
- [screams]
- 好的。
- [尖叫]
- Squidward was wrong.
- 章鱼哥错了。
Didn't hurt him,
just made him disappear.
没有伤害他，
刚刚让他消失了。
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
Ah! Sea spider!
啊!海蜘蛛！
[metallic smashing]
[grunting]
[金属粉碎]
[咕噜声]
Uh!
[mumbles indistinctly]
呃！
[含糊不清地咕哝]
- Oh--oh, no, Patrick,
I'm slipping...
- 哦——哦，不，帕特里克，
我滑倒了...
and falling!
[screams]
和坠落！
[尖叫声]
[thud]
[砰]
I didn't even break a bone!
我连一根骨头都没有骨折！
- My turn!
- 轮到我了！
[stammering]
I'm losing my footing!
[结巴]
我快要失去立足点了！
No!
不！
I survived a deadly fall unhurt!
我从致命的坠落中幸存下来，没有受伤！
- Life insurance.
- 人寿保险。
- Hi-ya! Hi-ya!
- 嗨呀！嗨呀！
- What?
I can't hear you!
- 什么？
我听不到你说话！
- Hi-ya!
- 嗨呀！
- Turn the volume up
inside of your voice!
- 调高音量
在你的声音里！
- I said--
[screams]
- 我说--
[尖叫声]
[mumbles indistinctly]
[含糊不清地咕哝]
- Squidward,
what were you yelling?
- 章鱼哥，
你喊什么？
- I was trying to say
- 我想说
you got to fall
from something higher.
你必须跌倒
来自更高的东西。
- Sea spider!
- 海蜘蛛！
[smashing and grunting]
[粉碎和咕哝]
[whistles buzzing]
[口哨声响起]
- [startled mumbling]
- [吃惊的咕哝]
[splash]
Ah! My baby.
[飞溅]
啊！我的宝贝。
[grumbling]
[抱怨]
[whistles buzzing]
- Once again, I'm asking,
[口哨声响起]
- 我再一次问，
what are you doing?
- It's our final test.
你在干什么？
- 这是我们的最后测试。
We're trying to get
jellyfish to sting us
我们正在努力获得
水母蜇我们
to prove we can't get hurt.
来证明我们不会受伤。
- What?
- 什么？
- [inhales deeply]
[horn blares]
- [深吸一口气]
[喇叭声]
- Oh! Me! Me!
Sting me! Over here!
- 哦！我！我！
蜇我吧！在这里！
- Sting me, sting me, sting me.
- Blast me with your venom!
- 蜇我，蜇我，蜇我。
- 用你的毒液攻击我！
- Zap me with your pain juice!
- 用你的痛苦汁来攻击我！
- Sting me, please!
- Sting me, sting me, sting me.
- 请蜇我吧！
- 蜇我，蜇我，蜇我。
- You're the ones asking--
[zap]
- 你是在问的人--
[扎普]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- Gee, Squidward, maybe you
should get some life insurance.
- 哎呀，章鱼哥，也许是你
应该买一些人寿保险。
[crusty cracking]
- What are you yammering about?
[硬皮破裂]
- 你在抱怨什么？
- I bought some life insurance
for Patrick and myself,
- 我买了一些人寿保险
对于帕特里克和我自己来说，
and now we can never be hurt.
现在我们永远不会受到伤害。
- Yeah.
To test out the life insurance,
- 是的。
为了测试人寿保险，
we even built a super dangerous
obstacle course
我们甚至建造了一个超级危险的
障碍训练场
across the street.
街对面。
- We call it The Sushi Maker.
- 我们称之为寿司机。
[thunder booms]
[雷霆轰鸣]
Squidward, I think
you need this more than I.
我觉得章鱼哥
你比我更需要这个。
I would like to present you
with my life insurance policy.
我想向您介绍
和我的人寿保险单。
- [groans]
- Actually, you better take two,
- [呻吟]
- 事实上，你最好带两个，
since you're kind of a klutz.
因为你有点笨手笨脚。
[thud]
[grunts]
[砰]
[咕哝]
- Better take two?
Life insurance?
- 最好带两个？
人寿保险？
[growls] You giblet heads!
[咆哮]你们这些内脏头！
No piece of paper can protect
a person from getting hurt.
没有一张纸可以保护
一个人免遭伤害。
[both gasp]
- [whimpers]
[两人都喘气]
- [呜咽]
- Yay! It works!
- 耶！有用！
- You're untouchable!
- 你是不可触碰的！
- Oh, that was a coincidence.
- 哦，那是巧合。
- Driving's hard.
- 开车很难。
[tires squealing]
[轮胎吱吱声]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
both: Yay! Life insurance!
两人：耶！人寿保险！
- You are
magically protected.
- 你是
受到魔法保护。
-Whoo-hoo!
- Whoo!
-呼呼！
- 呼！
- Oh, it was luck!
Dumb luck!
- 哦，这真是运气好！
运气真好啊！
[thunder rumbling]
[雷声隆隆]
Look, I'll prove it.
You stand here.
听着，我会证明这一点。
你站在这里。
[zapping]
[both wailing]
[电击]
[双双哀嚎]
- Huh? Hmm? Oh.
- 啊？唔？哦。
- You see, Squidward?
You're immune!
- 你看到了吗，章鱼哥？
你已经免疫了！
- You can't be hurt!
- Yeah!
- 你不能受伤！
- 是的！
- You are a cast-iron
Squidward.
- 你是铸铁
章鱼哥。
both: Life insurance!
Life insurance!
两者：人寿保险！
人寿保险！
- Wow, I can't believe it,
- 哇，我简直不敢相信，
but you two sub-geniuses
were right somehow.
但你们两个次天才
不知何故是对的。
I can't be broken.
I'm indestructible!
我不能被打破。
我是坚不可摧的！
I am shatterproof!
我是防碎的！
Watch this.
[pop]
注意这个。
[流行音乐]
[cheerful ukulele music]
【欢快的尤克里里音乐】
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
- What you gonna do,
Squidward?
- 你要做什么，
章鱼哥？
- What does it look like?
- 它看起来像什么？
I'm running into a...
我遇到了一个...
[fabric tears]
Wall!
[布料的眼泪]
墙！
*
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
Yes.
That's just what it needed.
是的。
这正是它所需要的。
I'll call the painting
"One Hole."
我会给这幅画打电话
“一个洞。”
Oh, it's genius!
哦，真是天才！
[both panting]
[fabric tears]
[两人都气喘吁吁]
[布料的眼泪]
Ugh! Three holes?
啊!三孔？
That makes no sense!
这毫无意义！
- Did you see that?
- 你看到了吗？
I ran right through
a brick wall.
我直接跑过去
一堵砖墙。
I'm hard as nails!
我就像钉子一样坚硬！
Come on, world!
Bring it on!
加油吧，世界！
来吧！
- Hmm.
[panting]
- 唔。
[气喘吁吁]
- Oh, perfect.
- 哦，完美。
- [slurping]
- [发出声音]
- Pfft. Big tough guy.
- 噗。大硬汉。
- What are you doing,
Squidward?
- 你在做什么，
章鱼哥？
- Just watch.
- 就看吧。
- [slurps]
[grumbles]
- [啜饮]
[抱怨]
- Enjoying your sherbert,
Herbert?
- 享受你的果子露，
赫伯特？
- My name's not Herbert.
- 我的名字不是赫伯特。
- Oh, I know it's not.
- 哦，我知道不是。
Your name is "Hey."
What's your name?
你的名字叫“嘿”。
你叫什么名字？
[smack]
- Hey!
[咂]
- 嘿！
- Told ya!
Here, let me help you.
- 告诉你了！
在这里，让我来帮助你。
[wallop]
- [groans]
[冲击力]
- [呻吟]
- Funny, didn't feel a thing.
- 有趣的是，没有任何感觉。
- Uh, Squidward, I don't think
you should lick that.
- 呃，章鱼哥，我不认为
你应该舔那个。
It's got germs.
- Ha! Germs can't hurt me.
它有细菌。
- 哈！细菌无法伤害我。
Nothing can hurt me!
没有什么可以伤害我！
[germs screaming]
[细菌尖叫]
[whoosh]
[嗖嗖]
[splat]
[啪嗒]
As a matter of fact,
事实上，
do you know
what I'm gonna do now?
你知道吗
我现在要做什么？
I'm gonna run your
super dangerous obstacle course.
我要运行你的
超级危险的障碍赛。
You know why?
你知道为什么吗？
- Mm-mm.
- No.
- 嗯嗯。
- 不。
- Because now I've got moxie!
- 因为现在我有勇气了！
[both scream]
[两人尖叫]
both: Wait, what's moxie?
两人：等等，莫西是什么？
[heavy metal music]
[重金属音乐]
*
- [yawns]
- [哈欠]
*
[legs clattering]
[腿嘎嘎作响]
- What goes on, boyos?
- 发生什么事了，男孩？
- Squidward is gonna try out
The Sushi Maker.
- 章鱼哥要尝试一下
寿司师傅。
- Why does he want to do that?
- Oh, don't worry, Mr. Krabs.
- 他为什么要这么做？
-哦，别担心，蟹老板。
He's got life insurance.
He can't be hurt.
他有人寿保险。
他不能受伤。
- That's not how
life insurance works.
- 不是这样的
人寿保险有效。
- It's not?
- Course not!
- 它不是？
- 当然不是！
Life insurance is money
the beneficiary gets
人寿保险就是钱
受益人得到
when a person dies.
当一个人去世时。
By the way, who gets the money?
顺便问一下，谁能拿到钱？
- Well, let's see.
- 好吧，让我们看看。
[slide whistle ascending]
[滑哨上升]
No name here.
- Hooray!
这里没有名字。
- 万岁！
Hmm.
唔。
[pen clicks]
[笔点击]
[mumbling]
Eugene H. Krabs.
[咕哝]
尤金·克拉布斯 (Eugene H. Krabs)
Go, Squidward!
走吧，章鱼哥！
Yay!
耶！
Fly high! Do or die!
飞得更高！要么做，要么死！
Preferably the latter.
[cackles]
最好是后者。
[咯咯笑]
- D-d-d-d-do or die?
- D-D-D-D-做还是死？
Squidward, come down!
章鱼哥，下来！
You're not invincible!
你不是无敌的！
Life insurance
is not what you think!
人寿保险
不是你想的那样！
You were right!
Oh, it was just dumb luck.
你是对的！
哦，这只是运气不好。
- Now I'm yelling too!
- 现在我也大喊大叫了！
- Oh, what are those ninnies
going on about now?
-哦，那些傻瓜是什么？
现在正在进行什么？
I can't hear you!
我听不到你说话！
Just shut up and watch me.
闭嘴，看着我。
[plop]
Nah--hey!
[扑通]
不——嘿！
- Come back, Squidward!
Don't do this!
- 回来吧，章鱼哥！
不要这样做！
- Will you stop shaking it?
- 你能停止摇动它吗？
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[bubbles gurgling]
[咕噜咕噜的泡泡]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[clunk]
[沉闷]
[slide whistle
ascends and descends]
[幻灯片哨子
上升和下降]
[clunk]
[沉闷]
[thud]
[machine hisses]
[砰]
[机器嘶嘶声]
No, no, no, no, no!
不，不，不，不，不！
[sticky scrunches]
[strained shouting]
[粘稠的皱褶]
[紧张的喊叫]
[pop]
[流行音乐]
[wallops and groans]
[冲击力和呻吟声]
*
[splatters and groans]
[mechanical rattling]
[飞溅和呻吟]
[机械嘎嘎声]
Ow...
Eeh! Eeh! Eeh!
噢...
呃！呃！呃！
[muffled shouting]
[mechanical humming]
[低声喊叫]
[机械嗡嗡声]
[cannon booms]
[screams]
[大炮隆隆]
[尖叫声]
[clunk]
[groans]
[沉闷]
[呻吟]
[bell ringing]
[铃声响起]
[thud]
[grunts]
[砰]
[咕哝]
[kids chattering indistinctly]
[squeaking and honking]
[孩子们含糊不清地叽叽喳喳]
[吱吱声和喇叭声]
Ow...
噢...
- Hey, Squidward,
guess what I learned today.
- 嘿，章鱼哥，
猜猜我今天学到了什么。
Apparently,
a life insurance policy
显然，
人寿保险单
doesn't protect
a person from injury.
不保护
一个人免受伤害。
Heh, how about that?
- Ha, how 'bout that?
呵呵，那怎么样？
- 哈，那怎么样？
[spits]
[吐口水]
- Squidward, how did you survive
The Sushi Maker?
- 章鱼哥，你是怎么活下来的
寿司师傅？
[pop]
[grunts]
[流行音乐]
[咕哝]
It had to be this.
一定是这个。
- Ah!
both: Sea spider!
- 啊！
两人：海蜘蛛！
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
[upbeat seafaring music]
[欢快的航海音乐]